Look at us, getting ready for a double date with actual women...
Regarde-nous. Dire qu'on va sortir avec nos copines
...who publicly acknowledge they're our girlfriends.
qui reconnaissent publiquement nos relations.
Yes. I mean, actual women are the best.
C‘est mieux quand elles sont vraies.
I don't understand. What other kind of women are there?
Je ne comprends pas. Il y a d'autres sortes de femmes ?
Artificial women are your department. You wanna take this?
Tu réponds ? C‘est ton rayon, les femmes artificielles.
No, it would just freak him out.
Non. Ça lui ferait peur.
Listen, before we leave, I should warn you...
Avant de partir, je voudrais te dire
...l'm a passionate man...
que je suis un passionné
...and I tend towards public displays of affection.
et que je montre mon affection en public.
What are you trying to tell me, Howard?
Qu'essaies-tu de me dire, Howard ?
There might be making out in the car or restaurant.
On risque de s‘embrasser dans la voiture.
I don't want Bernadette to feel uncomfortable...
Pour que Bernadette ne soit pas gênée,
...so it would help if you and Penny made out too.
ce serait bien que Penny et toi fassiez pareil.
Don't worry, we're planning to have sex right on the salad bar.
Pas de souci. On a prévu de faire l‘amour sur la table.
Namaste, white people.
Namaslé, hommes blancs.
Good news. I've rented us...
Regardez ! J'ai loué
-...the four-hour edition of Watchmen. -Got it.
- le film Watchmen. - Je l‘ai.
-Seen it. -Detailed analysis posted online.
- Déjà vu. - J'en ai fait une critique détaillée.
Then what are we gonna do tonight?
Et on fait quoi ce soir ?
Sorry. Howard and l are going out with Penny and Bernadette.
Nous sortons avec Penny et Bernadette.
Yeah, no more carefree bachelor nights for me and Leonard.
Plus de soirée entre célibataires insouciants.
These broncos have been saddled.
On est des étalons domptés.
How did we get actual women?
Comment c‘est possible ?
Great. They get girlfriends and they just abandon us?
Ils ont des copines et nous abandonnent ?
It is great, isn't it?
C‘est super, non ?
We have a wonderful evening ahead of us.
Une super soirée s'annonce.
-We do? -Oh, yes.
- Vraiment ? - Oui.
I discovered I don't have enough room on my hard drive for a LINUX partition.
Mon disque dur n‘a plus de place pour une partition Linux.
You and l are gonna perform a full backup, reinitialize...
On va sauvegarder, réinitialiser
...and then reinstall all my operating systems.
et réinstaller mes systèmes.
-I don't wanna do that. -All right.
- Je ne le ferai pas. - Bien.
Well, I'm going to perform a full backup, reinitialize...
Je vais sauvegarder, réinitialiser
...and then reinstall all my operating systems.
et réinstaller mes systèmes.
Well, what about me?
Et moi ?
Well, I understand there are several types of artificial women.
J'ai compris qu'il y a plusieurs sortes de femmes artificielles.
Maybe you should look into that.
Une piste à creuser.
Dude, there are so many cool things we could be doing tonight. Look.
Il y a plein de trucs cools à faire ce soir.
At the Glendale Galleria: "Put on your best zoot suit.
Ala Galerie Glendale: ”Mettez votre costume zazou
It's a salute to swing music...
pour un hommage au twist
...in the center court near Macy's, 5 pm. to 9 pm."
devant chez Macy‘s à partir de 17 h."
A salute to zoot.
Un hommage au zazou.
-Sounds like a hoot. -l'm sorry, Raj.
- Ça a l‘air drôle. - Désolé, Ra].
l have no desire to salute any article of clothing tonight...
Je n'ai pas envie de rendre hommage à un habit
...much less one that's linked to race riots in the 1940s.
encore moins à un lié aux émeutes raciales des années 40.
Race riots?
Des émeutes raciales ?
The Zoot Suit Riots.
Les émeutes zazous.
I always thought that was some sort of after-Christmas sale.
Je pensais que c‘était un genre de soldes aprés Noël.
Why don't we go to the galleria and walk around?
On pourrait se promener àla Galerie ?
I don't need anything at the galleria. You need anything at the galleria?
Je n'ai besoin de rien àla Galerie. Toi, si ?
No, we would just walk around and see what's what.
Je veux regarder etjeter un œil.
That's a semantically null sentence.
C‘est une tautologie.
Okay, well, how about this? From the university website:
D‘accord. Et ça ? Sur le site de l'université :
"Seven pm. to 10 p.m., Norton Hall Multipurpose Room...
"De 19 h à 22 h, àla salle polyvalente,
...mixer for grad students and faculty...
rencontre étudiants - enseignants
...of the Science and Humanities Departments.
des facultés de sciences et de lettres.
Whether you split atoms or infinitives, this is the place to be."
Que vous étudiez les atomes ou les mots, soirée à ne pas manquer."
Well, that's certainly amusing...
C‘est sûrement amusant
...but I have no interest.
mais sans intérêt.
Come on, Sheldon.
Allez, Sheldon.
The world is filled with people doing things outside.
Le monde est plein de choses à faire.
Let's go outside. Outside is good.
Sortons. L‘extérieur est bon.
If outside is so good...
Si l‘extérieur est bon,
...why has mankind spent thousands of years trying to perfect inside?
pourquoi l'humanité essaie d‘améliorer l‘intérieur ?
I don't know. It's a marketing scheme.
C‘est un marché lucratif ?
Please, Sheldon, I'm a young, virile visitor from a foreign land...
Je suis un viril visiteur d‘une contrée lointaine
...and I need to strut my stuff.
etj'ai besoin de frimer.
Let me offer you a compromise.
J'ai une idée.
Sometimes when I feel stifled and want a change of scenery...
Quand je me sens oppressé et que je veux changer d'air,
...I use my imagination.
j‘utilise mon imagination.
Oh, boy.
Mon Dieu.
One of my favorite places to visit is the two-dimensional world...
J'aime Visiter le monde en deux dimensions
...described in Edwin Abbott's mathematical fantasy Flatland.
décrit par Edwin Abbott, Finland.
I don't wanna go to Flatland.
Je ne veux pas y aller.
You're only saying that because you haven't been there.
Tu dis ça, car tu n‘y es jamais allé.
lam now a hexagon in two-dimensional space...
Je suis un hexagone dans un espace bidimensionnel
...and can only perceive the edges of other objects.
etje peux percevoir le bord des autres objets.
Is that you, Raj? I don't recognize your edge.
C‘est toi, Raj ? Je ne reconnais pas ton bord.
Sheldon, I'm begging you.
Je t'en supplie.
I want to go to this mixer, and I don't want to go alone.
Je ne veux pas aller seul à cette rencontre.
Well, you're in luck. There's a mixer here in Flatland.
Tu es chanceux. Il y a une rencontre à Flatland.
Oh, look.
Regarde !
There's a sexually attractive line segment.
Il y a une ligne sexuellement attirante.
-Chat her up. -What?
- Drague—la. - Quoi ?
Tell her you're a circle. Flatland gals are all hot for circles.
Dis que tu es un cercle. Les nanas de Flatland aiment ça.
I hope you're hungry. We're going to a terrific restaurant.
Tu as faim ? On va dans un super restaurant.
Oh, yeah, I'm starved. When you spend all day in a bio lab...
Je suis affamée. Etudier toute lajournée
...watching flesh-eating bacteria skeletonize rodents...
des bactéries carnivores qui mangent,
...it really works up an appetite.
ça ouvre l'appétit.
Flesh-eating bacteria and yet I still wanna kiss this woman.
Des bactéries etj'ai envie de l‘embrasser ?
What does that tell you?
Ça veut dire quoi ?
You'd be willing to die a horrible death...
Que tu es prêt à mourir pour atteindre la deuxième base.
We're way past second base. Right, Howard?
On a déjà atteint cette base, pas vrai ?
Well, we kind of disagree about what the bases are.
On n‘est pas d'accord sur la définition des bases.
How's your work going, Penny? Any acting jobs?
Comment ça se passe le travail ?
The last big thing I did was this production...
Mon dernier rôle était dans
...of Diary ofAnne Frank above a bowling alley.
Le Journal d‘Anne Frank, dans un bowling.
But I think things might be turning around pretty soon.
Mais la chance va bientôt tourner.
Well, great. How come?
Super ! Comment ?
Well, promise you won't make fun of me?
Tu ne te moques pas de moi ?
Of course. I would never make fun of you.
Je ne moquerai jamais de toi.
Okay, well, I went to this psychic who told me that if I cut my hair...
D‘après une voyante, si je me fais couper les cheveux,
...l'm gonna get a national commercial.
je jouerai dans une publicité nationale.
What? Seriously?
Quoi ? Sérieusement ?
You're getting career advice from a psychic?
Tu demandes des conseils à une voyante ?
Good job not making fun of her.
Heureusement que tu ne te moques pas d‘elle.
She's not one of those phonies, okay? She wrote a book, has her own website.
Une vraie voyante. Elle a écrit un livre et a un site.
Oh, gee, why didn't you say so?
Il fallait le dire.
They don't just let anyone have a website.
On ne laisse pas n‘importe qui créer un site.
-Why are you being such ajerk? -You're surprised?
- Tu réagis comme un idiot. - Ça t'étonne ?
Your psychic didn't tell you I was going to be ajerk?
Ta voyante ne te l‘avait pas dit ?
-Come on, Penny. -Why don't you kids go ahead and chat?
- Allons, Penny. - Continuez à papoter.
We're gonna make out back here.
On va s'embrasser.
I'm sliding into third.
Je glisse vers la troisième base.
Thanks for coming with me.
Merci d'être venu.
Thanks for giving me your limited edition Green Lantern lantern.
Merci de m‘avoir donné ta lanterne de collection Green Lantern.
Did you really have to bring it with you?
Tu étais obligé de l'apporter ?
What if evil strikes and my power ring runs low?
Si le mal attaque et que je dois recharger mon anneau ?
-Come on, let's get a drink. -I don't drink.
- Buvons un verre. - Je ne bois pas.
And when my wingman is carrying a Green Lantern lantern, I drink a lot.
Et quand mon complice se promène avec une lanterne, je bois encore plus.
I'll have a screwdriver, please. And don't be chintzy with the screw.
Je prendrai une vodka—orange. Avec beaucoup de vodka.
I would like a root-beer float.
Un café glacé.
-Sheldon, they don't have ice cream. -They don't?
- Ils n‘ont pas de glace. - Vraiment ?
Well, apparently these people and l differ greatly on the definition of "party."
Nous avons une définition différente du mot "fête".
-He'll have a Shirley Temple. -And don't be chintzy with the Shirley.
- Une grenadine. - Avec beaucoup de grenadine.
-Okay, let's check out the females. -All right.
- Voyons les femelles. - D‘accord.
There's a female.
Il y a une femelle.
That's Professor Wilkinson's wife. She's like 80.
La femme de M. Wilkinson. Elle a 80 ans.
But she's female. Isn't that the game?
C‘est une femelle. Ce n‘est pas la règle ?
-No. I'm looking for a hookup. -Oh, yes.
- Je cherche un coup. - D‘accord.
So the point of this exercise is for you to find someone to copulate with?
Le but de l'exercice est de te trouver une femme pour copuler.
Not so loud. But ideally, yes.
Pas si fort. Idéalement, oui.
-Thanks. -Thank you.
- Merci.
And what is my function as wingman?
Je fais quoi en tant que complice ?
-You help me run my game. -Okay.
- Tu m'aides à gagner. - D‘accord.
And what is your game?
Comment on joue ?
When I lie through my teeth to a woman, you nod and agree.
Quand je mens, tu hoches la tête et acquiesces.
Hey, that's pretty cool. What is it?
C‘est cool. C‘est quoi ?
It's a limited edition Green Lantern lantern.
C‘est une lanterne de collection Green Lantern.
My friend is looking for someone to copulate with.
Mon ami cherche quelqu'un pour copuler.
You're very funny. I'm Abby.
Tu es drôle. Je m‘appelle Abby.
-l'm Sheldon. -How do you do?
- Sheldon. - Ça va ?
Rajesh Ramayan Koothrappali. Call me Raj.
Rajesh Ramayan Koothrappali. Appelle—moi Raj.
-Hey, Raj. Where are you from? -The mysterious subcontinent of India.
- D'où viens-tu ? - Du mystérieux sous—continent de l‘Inde.
-Ooh. India. -You know India?
- L‘Inde. - Tu connais ?
-I saw Slumdog Millionaire. -Well, I'm a slumdog astrophysicist.
- SIumdog Millionaire. - Je suis astrophysicien des taudis.
I thought your father was a gynecologist.
Ton père n‘est pas gynécologue ?
I'm sorry.
Pardon.
Martha, come here. Meet Raj and Sheldon.
Martha, viens. Voici Raj et Sheldon.
-My friend Martha. -Hi.
- Martha. - Salut.
Is that the limited edition Green Lantern lantern?
C‘est la lanterne de collection Green Lantern ?
In brightest day, in darkest night, no evil shall escape my sight.
En plein jour ou en pleine nuit, aucun mal n‘échappe à mon regard.
Oh, that is so awesome.
C‘est génial.
Thank you.
Merci.
Have you chosen one to copulate with?
Tu en as choisi une ?
So, what should we talk about?
De quoi pouvons-nous parler ?
Well, we could always learn more...
On pourrait apprendre
...about why people who believe in psychics are idiots. Leonard?
en quoi ceux qui croient aux voyants sont idiots.
We don't need to talk about that anymore.
Pas besoin d'en parler.
Leonard covered it pretty well in the car.
Leonard a déjà tout dit.
I'm sorry, but facts are facts.
Désolé, mais les faits sont les faits.
Right, and if you can't understand it, it's not a fact.
Si tu ne le comprends pas, ce n‘est pas un fait.
No, if it's not a fact, it's not a fact.
Si ce n‘est pas un fait,
-Oh, got it. Thank you for educating me. -Oh, you're welcome.
- J'ai compris. Merci de m'instruire. - De rien.
-How's your fish? -Amazing.
- Ton poisson est bon ? - Divin.
-Would you like to try some? -Yeah, sure.
- Tu veux goûter ? - Oui.
Well, the fact is you can't.
Le fait est que tu ne peux pas.
Howard, Bernadette, you're both scientists.
Vous êtes des scientifiques.
Help me out here.
Aidez-moi.
Wannajump in the middle of another couple's argument?
Tu veux te mêler à une dispute ?
-No, thank you. -Sorry.
- Non, merci. - Désolé.
Maybe we should just stop talking about this.
On devrait arrêter d'en parler.
Maybe some of us should stop talking altogether.
Certains devraient arrêter de parler ensemble.
-How is everything tonight? -Really uncomfortable.
- Comment se passe le repas ? - Assez mai.
The best thing about a monogamous, mutually supportive relationship...
C‘est super, une relation solide et monogame.
...is even if you have different ideas...
En cas de désaccord,
...you can have a spirited debate, yet still care for, even make love--
on peut débattre, tout en s'aimant ou en faisant l'amour...
You want your fish?
Ton poisson ?
Knew you were gonna do that. Doesn't make me psychic.
Je le savais. Ça ne fait pas de moi un voyant.
Attaboy, Leonard. Make it worse.
Bravo, Leonard. Continue!
What's going on?
Que se passe-t-il ?
We scored.
On a gagné.
I'm the wingman.
Je suis le complice.
-Hey. -Laser.
- Salut. - Laser.
Had a great night last night.
Quelle super nuit!
I don't like to kiss and tell, but somebody made it to eighth base.
Je n'aime pas me vanter mais quelqu'un a atteint la huitième base.
-What the hell is eighth base? -Seventh base with shirt off.
- C'est-à-dire ? - La septième sans chemise.
Well, my shirt.
Enfin, ma chemise.
Are we taking our relationship frustrations out...
Tu passes ta frustration
...on innocent Cylons?
sur de pauvres Cylons ?
It's notjust Cylons. Superman's next.
Pas seulement. Superman est le prochain.
l was gonna try to squeeze in a little more mocking before lunch...
Je pensais me moquer de toi avant le repas
...but I can come back when you don't have a high-powered weapon.
mais je reviendrai quand tu ne seras plus armé.
How can I go out with a woman who believes in psychics?
Comment sortir avec une fille qui croit à la voyance ?
Hey, I once dated a girl who believed she was abducted by aliens.
Une de mes ex croyait avoir été enlevée par des aliens.
And that didn't bother you?
Ça ne te gênait pas ?
What am I supposed to do?
Je dois faire quoi ?
Pretend I believe something I don't when I'm with Penny?
Prétendre que j‘y crois pour elle ?
Hey, I'm sure Penny fakes all kinds of things when she's with you.
Je suis sûr que Penny fait semblant avec toi aussi.
Do me a favor. Lean over, put your head right here.
Aide-moi. Penche-toi et mets ta tête la.
Let me show you another way to look at this.
Vois-ça sous un autre angle.
Here we have the universe of all women.
Ici, c‘est l‘univers des femmes.
Okay, these are the ones you wanna sleep with.
La, celles avec qui tu veux coucher.
These are the women who believe exactly what you believe.
La, celles qui croient exactement comme toi.
who would be willing to sleep with you.
La, celles qui voudront coucher avec toi.
And right there, in the little triple intersection...
Et juste la, à cette intersection,
...is your ideal mate.
ta copine idéale.
Odds are she's a short physicist with low self-esteem...
Ce sera une physicienne sans assurance
...who lives in a government research facility in China.
qui vit dans un labo en Chine.
What's your point?
Tu en conclus quoi ?
To keep having a sexual relationship with Penny...
Pour avoir des relations sexuelles,
...l have to give up everything I believe in? My intellectual integrity?
je dois abandonner mes croyances ? Mon intégrité ?
The very nature of who I am? I can't do that, Howard.
Qui je suis ? C‘est impossible, Howard.
I respect that.
Je le respecte.
-What is that? -Your new girlfriend.
- C‘est ? - Ta nouvelle copine.
Have fun tonight.
Amuse—toi ce soir.
"The dog."
Le chien :
"The roof."
Le toit :
"Grapes."
Le raisin :
One minute.
Une minute.
-What was that? -It means, "Come in."
- C‘était quoi ? - "Entre."
It's taking forever to load the new operating system on my computer.
Le nouveau système est très long à installer.
l disinfected the kitchen and the bathroom.
J'ai désinfecté la cuisine.
Now I thought I'd learn Finnish.
Alors, j'apprends Ie finnois.
That's Hindi for, "Whatever floats your boat."
Ça veut dire : “Si ça te chante" en hindi.
Listen, I got a text from that girl Abby...
J'ai reçu un message d‘Abby.
...and she and Martha wanna hang out with us again.
Elle et Martha veulent sortir avec nous.
-What do you say? -I don't say anything.
- Qu'en dis-tu ? - Rien du tout.
l merely offer you a facial expression that suggests you've gone insane.
Je t‘offre plutôt une expression faciale qui suggère que tu es fou.
-I don't get it. You had a great time. -Yes, exactly. I had a great time.
- Je ne comprends pas. Tu t'es amusé. - Je me suis amusé.
That's done. I've moved on to other things.
Je suis passé à autre chose.
For example, after I learn Finnish, I'm not going to learn Finnish again.
Quand j‘aurai appris le finnois, je ne l'apprendrai plus.
Please, Sheldon.
S'il te plaît.
I'm a lost Indian boy far from home...
Je suis un Indien perdu
...and I want a girlfriend, and I want her to be Abby...
etje veux une copine. Je veux Abby
...and she'll only come if she can bring Martha.
et elle viendra seulement avec Martha.
I highly doubt there is any argument you can make...
Tu auras beau argumenter,
...threat you might levy, rhetorical strategy, plea, invocation...
me menacer, élaborer des stratégies, demander, invoquer,
...supplication or "vetoomus" that you can employ...
supplier ou vetoomus,
...that would convince me to reconsider.
ça ne changera rien.
My Incredible Hulk hands signed by Stan Lee.
Mes mains de L‘Incroyable Hulk signées par Stan Lee.
Oh, my.
Mon Dieu.
I've admired these for years.
Je les admire depuis des années.
Does that mean we can go out with the girls again?
Alors, on sort à nouveau ?
Hulk agree to second date with puny humans.
Hulk accepte second rencard avec humaines chétives.
You can't wear the hands on the date.
Tu ne prends pas les mains avec toi.
Hulk sad.
Hulk triste.
Cleaning out the old dryer lint, huh?
Tu nettoies les peluches du sèche—linge ?
Not only is it courteous, it's safety-smart.
C‘est courtois et intelligent.
Every year, 15,000 fires are caused by accidental dryer-lint ignition.
Tous les ans, 15 000 incendies sont causés par des sèche-linge.
And now you're supposed to say, "Wow, what an interesting fact.
Tu es censée dire: "C‘est passionnant.
Come here, you crazy, nerdy guy. I could never be mad at you."
Viens ici, mon petit intello. Je ne peux pas te faire la tête."
...on a double date that included Howard Wolowitz?
plus odieux qu'Howard Wolowitz à ce rencard ?
No, I'm sorry. I really am.
Non. Je suis vraiment désolé.
Thank you.
Merci.
You willing to go to my psychic and see what it's about?
Tu veux rencontrer ma voyante ?
You willing to read a book...
Tu veux lire mon livre
...that concisely explains how all psychics are frauds?
sur les voyants et les charlatans ?
-Okay, let's go see your psychic. -Really?
- Bien. Allons voir ta voyante. - Vraiment ?
Well, yeah. One of us has to keep an open mind.
L'un d‘entre nous doit être tolérant.
-Saying I don't have an open mind? -No. Let me help you with this stuff.
- Je ne suis pas tolérante ? - Laisse—moi t'aider.
You know, I believe in ghosts too.
Je crois aux fantômes.
-Great. -And astrology.
- Super. - A l‘astrologie.
I know. And pyramid power and healing crystals.
Je sais. Et aux pouvoirs des pyramides et des cristaux.
Oh, no, no, no. Crystals don't work.
Non. Les cristaux, ça ne fonctionne pas.
Really? That's the line?
Vraiment ? C‘est la limite ?
Psychics are real, but crystals are voodoo?
Les cristaux, c‘est du vaudou ?
Oh, voodoo's real. You don't wanna mess with voodoo.
Le vaudou existe. Faut pas rire avec ça.
Flatland is more than just a mathematical essay.
Flatland est plus qu'un essai mathématique.
It is also a treatise on Victorian social mores.
C‘est un traité sur les mœurs victoriennes.
You know, I had never considered that.
Je n‘avais jamais vu ça comme ça.
-Well, it's late. -Uh-huh.
Il est tard.
Time for bed.
L‘heure d‘aller au lit.
Okay.
D‘accord.
Good night, puny human.
Bonne nuit, humaine chétive.
Yes?
Oui ?
Listen, they're kind of getting busy in the living room...
Ils sont très occupés dans le salon.
...and l was wondering if I could hang out in here for a while.
Je me demandais si je pouvais entrer un instant.
Well, I suppose. Come in.
Je suppose que oui. Entré.
I'll sleep in Leonard's room. Good night.
Je vais dormir dans la chambre de Leonard.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]
[FRENCH]